# **Umer Syed**

# Technical Support Representative / Fullstack Developer

350 Haliburton Heights, Stittsville ON K2V0G4 226 791 5113 <u>usyed@solinkcorp.com</u>

Skills
HTML & CSS
PHP
С
VMWare
SQL
MySQL
NoSQL
MongoDB
Bash
Java
ReactJS
NodeJS
jQuery
Bootstrap
Git
Linux
Python
JavaScript
LUA
Microsoft Office

### **Profile**

Full-stack developer with a background in criminology and certifications from various universities. Strong foundation in React and NodeJS and enjoys solving puzzles and challenges. Creative, divergent thinking, and not afraid to challenge the norm. Possesses strong analytical and research skills and capable of managing multiple tasks to meet tight deadlines. Excellent communication skills and attention to detail, contributes to projects and propose solutions effectively. Several years of experience, with 2 years being in the healthcare IT sector.

# **Employment History**

#### System Engineer, Carestream Health Canada, Concord, ON

February 2021 - January 2023

- Managed escalated network, operating systems and database issues employing Solaris/Oracle environment
- Troubleshooting ASN and EDI issues and ensuring that errors/problems caused during order submission
- Utilized SQL queries in troubleshooting database issues
- Maintained and Troubleshooting SharePoint sites for Intra-dept notes and client modules kept on file
- Provided support to end users on installation, configuration and project support through managing hardware and software requirements
- Provided clear and concise directions to cross functional departments, documentation, customer correspondence to deliver network and product support
- Provided on site support to technical issues logged in the system
- Provided updates to management as defined in business processes and practices for accounts including detailed month end resolution

#### Certified Specialist, Best Buy, Ottawa, ON

October 2018 — February 2021

- Provided technical support to customers for hardware and software-related issues.
- Implemented advanced analytics and tracking to measure the performance of marketing campaigns
- Made recommendations for products, and services
- Team leader, health and safety team and member of the employee commitee

#### **Hobbies**

Co-Founder of MainFrame Gaming:

We host a variety of game servers, with custom LUA scripts to make a more custom and unique gaming experience! A friendly and large gaming community consisting of over 1000 members, 200+ active daily A friendly and large gaming community consisting of over 1000 members, 200+ active daily

	1.2	
Lar	ıgua	ages

English	
French	
Urdu	
Hindi	
Punjabi	

#### IT Lead, CanadaCars, Waterloo, ON

September 2017 - September 2018

- Managed the IT department and oversaw the development of new software and websites to enhance the online customer experience.
- Provided technical support to team members and ensured seamless integration of software systems.
- Assured all employees were up to date on the software used for their respective departments
- · Created interactive training modules for health and safety training

#### Parts and Service Advisor, Cambridge Hyundai, Cambridge, ON

June 2015 - January 2017

- Worked as a parts and service advisor and provided technical support to customers for their vehicles.
- Assisted with the sale of parts and services to improve customer satisfaction and increase revenue.
- Created spreadsheets to make for more efficient and accurate inventory and stock counts.

#### Customer Support Representative, Solink, Kanata, ON

May 2023 - August 2024

- Customer Service Excellence: Delivered top-notch customer service through live platforms, fostering positive client relationships.
- Technical Troubleshooting: Provided clients with expert assistance in basic technical troubleshooting, ensuring optimal performance of Solink-provided equipment on-site.
  - Proficient in network troubleshooting and adept at diagnosing physical equipment issues.
- Agile Team Collaboration: Collaborated effectively in an agile team environment with the support team to meet customer needs and swiftly address emerging issues.
- Ticket Management: Utilized Zendesk and JIRA suites to create comprehensive tickets, logging customer complaints and queries with precision.
  - Ensured the resolution of customer issues within specified SLA timeframes, maintaining a high level of customer satisfaction.

#### Technical Support Representative, Solink, Kanata, ON

August 2024 - Present

- Collaborative Technical Support: Worked in tandem with field technicians on-site, providing advanced technical support to guarantee the online and operational integrity of Solink products in client locations.
- Advanced Troubleshooting: Conducted complex troubleshooting using SSH and demonstrated expertise in navigating the QNAP operating system.
- Beyond CSR Level Support: Consistently addressed technical issues surpassing CSR level complexity, showcasing in-depth knowledge and problem-solving capabilities.
- Data Issue Validation: Specialized in the validation and troubleshooting of data issues, ensuring accurate and efficient resolution.

## Education

BA Criminology, Carleton University, Ottawa, ON

Full Stack Development with NodeJS Certification, Carleton University, Ottawa, ON

#### Various Certifications

- · Advanced Google Analytics Google
- · Machine Learning Stanford University
- CS50's Introduction to Artificial Intelligence with Python Harvard University
- · CS50's Introduction to Game Development Harvard University

#### Projects:

- · Password Generator
- · ReadME Generator
- Team Profile Generator
- · Employee Tracker
- · Workday Scheduler
- Weather App
- Note Taker
- · Dispatch system mod for FiveM (MDT/CAD)
- · Custom LUA Framework for FiveM

#### **Extracurriculars**

- Volunteer Parking Services Waterloo Masjid
- · Juniour Achievement and DECA Volunteer Coordinator
- UW Hackathons

## References

William Shirk from Solink 6133152309 <u>wshirk@solinkcorp.com</u>

Tremaine Inyang from Best Buy Canada 6132620577 <u>tinyang@bbfs.ca</u>

Yousuf Qureshi from Carestream Health Canada 905-699-1324 <u>qyousuf@gmail.com</u>

Orooj Alam from CanadaCars
519-504-3909 oroojalam@yahoo.com